

Sr. Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, SQL Server , SSIS , SSRS, SSAS, Power BI , Azure Data Factory



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Happiest Minds Technologies Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Sr. Software Engineer, Software Development, Application Programming, TFS, VSS, GitHub, GitLab, Power

BI,SSAS,SSRS,ADF.SQL Server

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

## Summary

Having 5+ years of Professional experience in IT industry as a MSBI ETL & Report developer with extensive usage of ETL & Reporting tools like SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), SQL Server Reporting Service (SSRS), SQL Server Analysis Service (SSAS), ADF and Power BI.

Interacting with Business users, gathering and analyzing requirements.

Worked on Creating Analysis and mapping documents.

Have Good experience in developing packages for implementing business logic through Stored procedures and ETL packages using different types of Tasks, Transformations, Sources, and destinations.

Unit testing the SSIS packages and SSRS reports with respect to its flow and performance issues.

Implemented Error handling and utilized Event handlers for automated notifications using SSIS.

Extensive experience with SQL Server and T-SQL in constructing Temporary Tables, Table variables, Triggers, Tables, CTE, views, Procedures, functions, Indexes.

# **Work Experience**

# **Happiest Minds Technologies** as Senior Software Engineer Mar 2019 to Till Date

- \* Interacting with Business users, gathering and analyzing requirements.
- \* Worked on Creating Analysis and mapping documents.
- \* Have Good experience in developing packages for implementing business logic through Stored procedures and ETL packages using different types of Tasks, Transformations, Sources, and destinations.
- \* Unit testing the SSIS packages and SSRS reports with respect to its flow and performance issues.
- \* Implemented Error handling and utilized Event handlers for automated notifications using SSIS.
- \* Extensive experience with SQL Server and T-SQL in constructing Temporary Tables, Table variables, Triggers, Tables, CTE, views, Procedures, functions, Indexes.
- \* Created complex SQL queries by joining multiple tables, sub queries in TSQL.
- \* Implemented Performance Tuning at various levels.
- \* Have experience in designing/building reports/dashboards using Filters (Slicers), Drill-down Reports in Power BI Desktop.
- \* Good in writing DAX queries/expressions in power bi desktop.
- Experience in providing the securities for Power BI reports/dashboards by assigning roles.
- Designed different Types of SSRS reports like Drill Down, Drill Through, Sub reports, Parameterized, Cascading,

Matrix, Stepped Matrix, text reports and testing for quality and finally review with the customer to ensure the solution meets requirements.

- Worked on Complex SSRS reports which are using Dynamic SQL Queries.
- Involved in scheduling the reports and Subscriptions.
- Experience to use SQL Profiler for troubleshooting and optimization of SQL Server.
- Have experience on Azure Data factory (ADF) and ADL and Blob Storage.
- Experience with Azure transformation projects and implement ETL and data movement solutions using Azure Data Factory(ADF), SSIS.
- Performed unit and system testing, troubleshooting and bug fixing in Prod and QA environments.
- Have experience in creating cube and modifying measures and attributes, creating hierarchies and relationships in dimensions.
- Have experience on Crystal reports conversion to SSRS reports and Good experience on MS Excel.
- Followed agile methodology and coordinated daily scrum meetings.
- Worked closely with the team in meeting the deadlines pertaining to design and development deliverables.
- Have experience on using GitHub and GitLab.
- Excellent analytical and interpersonal skills, oral and written communication skills.

### Envoy Mortgage India Pvt Itd as Application Developer

Dec 2015 to Feb 2019

**HP Enterprise** as MSBI Developer Aug 2015 to Dec 2015

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2012

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
SQL Server 2008r2, 2012,2017	2012,2017	2021	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
Power BI, SQL Server Reporting Services	2012,2017	2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
TFS, VSS ,GitHub, GitLab		2021	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS)		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Azure Data Factory (ADF)		2021	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SSIS	2012,2017	2021	5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH	Expert			
HINDI	Expert			
KANNADA	Expert			
TELUGU	Expert			

## **Projects**

Project Title: 2012,2017 Client: Ascend Learning

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2019 - Till Date Project Location: Bangalore

Role: Sr. Programmer

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 8

Skill Used: MS SQL Server, SQL Server Integration Services, SQL Server Reporting Services, SQL Server Development, T-

SQL, Power Bi, SQL Azure, Azure Data Facory

Role Description: Worked on MSBI ETL & Report developer with extensive usage of ETL & Reporting tools like SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), SQL Server Reporting Service (SSRS), SQL Server Analysis Service (SSAS), ADF and Power BI.

Project Details: Ascend have served a variety of industries; the common thread throughout is education domain. They have helped people reach their career goals through education, training and certification. Their atmosphere of cross-business collaboration is expanding and connects people from different spheres that include not only education/ training but also Healthcare, Capital Markets, Property management and Insurance services etc. In our project each service is taken care by a Module within the application and we do design and maintain client specific reports for the same.

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time